[The La's singing
"There She Goes"]
♪ There she goes ♪
♪ There she goes again ♪
♪ Racing through my brain ♪
♪ And I just can't contain ♪
♪ This feeling that remains.. ♪
Please, Luke.
Please, please, please.
How many cups have
you had today?
- None.
- 'Plus.'
Five, but
yours is better.
- You have a problem.
- Yes, I do.
- 'Junkie.'
- Angel.
You've got
wings, baby.
[phone ringing]
Luke's?
Yeah.
You make that
look really good.
Oh, it is really good.
It's the best coffee in town.
- Oh, yeah? I'll get a cup.
- Good plan.
Yeah, I've never
been here before.
Just, uh, passing through
on my way to Hartford.
You're a regular Jack Kerouac.
Yeah.
You mind if I sit down?
Oh, you know what? Actually,
I'm meeting someone so I..
- I'm Joey.
- Okay.
- What, you don't have a name?
- No, I do have a name.
I just, I'm really
meeting someone, so..
So I guess
I should get going.
- So soon?
- What?
I'm just screwing
with your mind.
It's nice to meet you.
Enjoy Hartford.
Enjoy your coffee,
mystery woman.
Hm. I like that.
Hey. It's freezing.
Oh, what do you need?
Hot tea, coffee?
- Lip gloss.
- Aha.
I have vanilla,
chocolate, strawberry
and toasted
marshmallow.
Anything in there not
resembling a breakfast cereal?
Yes.
It has no smell but it changes
colors with your mood.
RuPaul doesn't
need this much makeup.
You're crabby.
I'm sorry. I lost my Macy Gray
CD and I need caffeine.
- I have your CD.
- Thief.
Sorry, I'll get
you some coffee.
What? It's not for me.
It's for Rory, I swear.
- You're shameless.
- Look, Officer Krupke.
She's right at that table,
right over there.
Ah. He's got quite
a pair, this guy.
Thanks.
Yeah, I've never been
through here before.
Oh, you have, too.
- Oh, hi.
You really like
my table, don't you?
I was just, uh..
Getting to know
my daughter.
- Your..
- Are you my new daddy?
Wow. You do not look old enough
to have a daughter.
No, I mean it. And you do not
look like a daughter.
That's possibly very
sweet of you. Thanks.
So...daughter.
You know, I am traveling
with a friend.
- She's sixteen.
- Bye.
Drive safe.
[ Carole King singing
"Where You Lead"]
♪ If you're out on the road ♪
♪ Feeling lonely and so cold ♪
♪ All you have to do
is call my name ♪
♪ And I'll be there
on the next train ♪
♪ Where you lead,
I will follow ♪
♪ Anywhere that you tell me to ♪
♪ If you need, you
need me to be with you ♪
♪ I will follow ♪
♪ Where you lead ♪
♪ I will follow anywhere ♪
♪ That you tell me to ♪
♪ If you need, you
need me to be with you ♪
♪ I will follow
where you lead me ♪
[music]
- Here you go.
- Thanks.
Independence Inn,
Michel speaking.
No, I'm sorry,
we're completely booked.
We have a wedding
party here.
No, there is really
nothing I can do.
Yes, I'm sure.
Positive.
No, I don't have
to look ma'am, I--
Yes, of course
I'll look.
No, I'm sorry,
we're completely booked.
(female #1)
'Oh, no, don't move.'
Just ignore
the tiny woman pushing
the 200-pound
instrument around.
'No, this is good, I like this''
After this I'll, uh,
bench press a piano, huh?
Oh, that's it, lady,
tie your shoe now.
Yeah, don't worry,
I'll wait.
Hi, Drella, hi.
I was just wondering, um, could
you be, uh, nicer to the guests?
I'm sorry. Did you not
want a harp player?
Yes, I did.
And did you not want
a great harp player?
Yes, I did.
Okay. I am a great harp player.
And this is my
great harp, okay?
So if you're looking for someone
to be nice to the guests
get a harmonica player.
Maybe someone who whistles
through his nose.
Okay? Capish?
Oh, that is a great spot for a
table. Decorator's a genius.
Madame, you have no idea how
desperately I'd like to help.
But see, I'd have to build
a room for you myself
and I'm a man
who works with his hands.
So the best I can do
is suggest that you
please try for another
weekend. Any weekend.
Ah, good, fine,
the twenty-first.
Hold on, I'll look.
No, I'm sorry,
we're completely booked.
Has the plumber attended
to room four yet?
He was here, he did nothing,
it's a hundred dollars.
Hi, Marco, Lorelai.
Talk to me about room four.
What was wrong with it?
Uh-huh? I thought
you replaced that already.
Well, because you told me you
did and I never forget anything.
So this one's on you, right?
Pleasure doing
business with you.
- What is your offspring doing?
- Need stamps. I'll take these?
- No.
- Take them.
- What's with the muumuu?
- Stop.
I'm just saying, you couldn't
find one made of metal
in case anyone
has X-ray eyes?
And now we
say goodbye.
Hey, have Michel look at your
French paper before you go.
- Excuse me?
- That'd be great.
- No.
- Come on, Michel.
I'll tell all the ladies
what a stud you are.
Hm. I believe that memo
has already been sent.
[French accent]
Oh, please, Michel.
Pretty please with sucre on top.
I will stop
talking like this.
Leave it. I'll look
at it if I get a chance.
It's due tomorrow. And pay
attention to the grammar.
- I despise you.
- Hm.
When are you going
to let your parents know
that you listen to
the evil rock music?
You're an American teenager,
for God's sake.
Rory, if my parents still get
upset over the obscene
portion size of American food,
I seriously doubt
I'm gonna make any
inroads with Eminem.
- I have to go to that.
- The hayride? You're kidding
My parents set me up with the
son of a business associate.
He's gonna be a doctor.
- How old is he?
- Sixteen.
So he's gonna be a doctor
in a hundred years.
Well, my parents
like to plan ahead.
God, you have to go to the
hayride with him?
- And his older brother.
- Oh, now you're kidding.
Koreans never joke
about future doctors.
So, I guess you're
not going, huh?
No, I'm still fuzzy on
what's fun about sitting in
the cold for two hours with
some sticks up your butt.
Don't expect me to
clear it up for you.
For those of you who
have not finished
the final chapters of
Huckleberry Finn
'you may use
this time to do so.'
'For those of you who have, you
can start on your essay now.'
'Whichever task you choose,
do it silently.'
[softly]
Maybe it's a love letter.
- Or her diary.
- Could be a slam book.
It's the assignment.
[harp music]
- Nice, huh?
- Beautiful.
Yeah, well, tell it
to the tip jar.
Take Mrs. Langworthy's
bags up to 314.
Make sure the drapes are closed
and there's extra soap
and she wants her
pillow mints now.
[vessels clattering]
- Sookie!
- 'I'm okay, I'm okay.'
'What did you do now?'
Oh, why aren't
you watching her?
[speaking Spanish]
Eh, no, she's this.
Bad food in the head.
Oh.
I need you to be
more careful.
I know, I'm sorry.
Hey, I fixed the peach sauce.
That's blood, you're bleeding.
Why are you bleeding?
Oh, my stitches opened. I was
using too much maple syrup.
- It strangled the fruit.
- When did you get stitches?
- Friday night. Radish roses.
- Okay, stop moving.
You gotta taste
the sauce.
You have to try it
while it's warm.
Okay. Oh, Sookie, I need
you to be more careful.
I need there to be
fewer accidents.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Oh, dear God Almighty.
That's incredible.
I want to put it on
the waffles for breakfast.
- I wanna bathe in that sauce.
- I will make more.
Someday, when we open
our own inn.
Diabetics will line up
to eat this sauce.
- Won't that be great?
- Yeah.
But the key to someday
achieving that dream
is for you to stay alive,
so we can open an inn.
- Do you understand?
- Yes, I understand.
- Alright.
- Mm-hm.
So, now, let's get you up
and to the doctor on three.
- One, two, three.
- Ow!
- What?
- Stepped on my thumb. I'm fine.
(Sookie)
On three. Okay.
Was it a good
color at least?
- It had sparkles in it.
- Wow.
And it smelled like
bubble gum when it dried.
Oh, well, there's no way Mark
Twain can compete with that.
[bell rings]
Mom, we're home.
- Did you hear something?
- I'm not sure.
Mom? Are you here?
'We're open.
Everything's half off.'
We have contact.
- Mom?
- 'Lane?'
- Mom, where are you?
- 'Lane, where are you?'
- Back here.
- 'Over here!'
I think she's that way.
- Are we closer?
- 'I'm by the table!'
She's kidding, right?
Look, we'll meet you
in the kitchen!
- 'What?'
- The kitchen.
- 'Who's that?'
- It's Rory, Mom.
'Oh.'
Wow, I could hear the
disappointment from here.
Come on. Stop it.
It sucks that after all these
years your mom still hates me.
- She doesn't hate you.
- She hates my mother.
She doesn't trust
unmarried women.
You're unmarried.
I'm hay riding with a future
proctologist. I have potential.
Go upstairs.
Tea is ready.
I have muffins with no dairy,
no sugar, no wheat.
Have to soak them in tea
to make them soft to bite
but they're very healthy.
So, how was school?
None of the girls
get pregnant, drop out?
Not that we know of.
Come to think of it,
Joanna Posner was glowing.
- What?
- Nothing, she's just kidding.
Boys don't like funny girls.
Noted.
(male #1)
'Hello? Is Anybody here?'
We're here.
We're coming!
Have the muffins made
from sprouted wheat.
Only good 24 hours.
Everything's half off!
- 'Where are you?'
- Over here.
- 'Where?'
- 'By the chair!'
'What chair?'
- 'Careful!'
- I'm okay.
- Peppers, peppers, peppers.
- Mike!
Okay, hello little
vegetables, come with me.
I got that.
Okay, where's my glaze?
- In the counter.
- On the counter.
On, not in, not in the counter.
Okay, good, alright. My sauce.
Who-o, that's pretty good.
Hello, a little bit of greens.
Okay, okay. Hello, my little
babies. You like that?
A little bit of juice. Okay.
You're very pretty. Okay.
Mike, Mike!
Sookie!
O-oh, It's here.
It happened. She did it.
I'm gonna need a little
bit longer sentence.
The Chilton school.
Rory got in.
Oh my God!
I know. Look.
"Dear Ms. Gilmore, We are happy
to inform you that we have
"a vacancy at Chilton
Preparatory starting immediately
"due to your daughter's
excellent credentials
"and your enthusiastic
pursuit of her enrollment.
I offered to do
the principal.
"We'll be happy to accept her,
once the first semester's
tuition has
been received."
This is very exciting.
[both giggling]
- Is something burning?
- My bangs, earlier.
- Go on, go on, go on.
- This is it.
She can go to Harvard and get
the education I couldn't.
Do things that I couldn't.
Then I can resent her for it
and we can finally have a normal
mother-daughter relationship.
Oh, good.
- 'Mom?'
- Oh.
- You're happy.
- Yeah.
- Did you do something slutty?
- I'm not that happy.
[chuckling]
- Here.
- What's going on?
Open it.
I'm gonna be in
a Britney Spears video?
You're going to Chilton!
Oh, sorry.
- Mom?
- You did it, babe. You got in.
How did this happen? You didn't,
with the principal, did you?
No, honey,
that was a joke.
They have an open spot.
You're gonna start on Monday.
- Really?
- Really.
I don't believe this.
Oh my God, I'm going to Chilton!
Yeah.
- Sookie, I'm going to Chilton.
- I'll make cookies.
- Protestants love oatmeal.
- I have to call Lane.
- I love you.
- My girl's going to Chilton.
- Yeah. Rory's going to Chilton!
Rory's going to Chilton!
'Rory's going to Chilton!'
- Michel, the phone.
- Mm-hm. It rings.
- Can you answer it?
- No.
People are particularly stupid
today. I can't talk anymore.
You know who's really
nice to talk to?
The people at
the unemployment agency.
Independence Inn,
Michel speaking.
No, I'm sorry,
we're completely booked.
I'm holding for Miss Bell.
I've been trying all day.
Lorelai Gilmore.
Hi! Oh, hi, hi. Yeah, uh, my
daughter Rory has just been
accepted, yay.
Thank you, and, um
I got the invoice
for your enrollment fee.
Wow, that is a lot of zeros
behind that five.
Uh-huh. Okay, well, I guess what
I'm wondering is if you couldn't
take, say, part of it now,
just to get her going?
Well, but she's supposed
to start Monday.
It just doesn't give me a lot
of time to pull a bank job.
Well, never mind,
I was just kidding.
No, a bank job is
robbing a bank but..
Uh-huh. Oh, no. No, no, no.
I don't want you to give up
her space. I'll just...
I'll have to figure it out.
Okay. No, thank you. It's been
a real treat talking to you.
Yeah. Bye-bye.
What do I do? What do I do?
What do I do?
You can have anything I own.
My car! Sell my car.
- No one wants your car.
- Yeah.
There's something I haven't
thought of, I know.
There's something staring
me right in the face.
I just...I haven't seen it.
You know, you might
consider calling your--
- No.
- But I don't think you--
- Stop.
- You can at least go--
- Uh.
- Okay.
Can I say something?
It's really your only option.
Sookie, there are
several chapters from
a Stephen King novel,
I'd reenact before I'd resort
to that option.
- Okay, dropped. Dropped.
- Thank you.
(Rory)
'Mom?'
- So what do you think?
- Wow, it makes you look smart.
Okay, no more wine
for you. Mom?
You look like you were
swallowed by a kilt.
Fine, you can
hem it. A little.
- Ooh.
- Only a little.
- Or I could hem it a lot.
- No. I don't want it too short.
I can't believe tomorrow's my
last day at Stars Hollow High.
I know.
I was so excited,
I dressed for gym.
- You're kidding!
- And I played volleyball.
With other people?
And all this time
I was avoiding group sports?
- Yeah.
- Was very smart 'cause I suck.
Well, yeah, you got
that from me.
- Where's your pate?
- At Zsa Zsa Gabor's house.
I'm going to the store
because there's nothing.
- You feel like duck?
- If it's made with chicken.
- I'll be back.
- 'Bye.'
[door closes]
Alright. This will
give you an idea.
- Go see how you like it.
- Okay.
I love being
a private school girl.
[Sam Phillips singing
"Where The Colors Don't Go"]
♪ In a white room ♪
♪ In a white head ♪
♪ In a cobweb of enterprise ♪
♪ Where the dreams sleep
and fears keep ♪
♪ That's where
the colors don't go ♪
the colors don't show ♪
♪ That's where
the colors don't go ♪
the colors don't show ♪
Hi, Mom.
Lorelai, my goodness,
this is a surprise.
- Is it Easter already?
- 'Ha, ha.'
No, I finished up my business
class and thought I'd stop by.
- To see me?
- 'Yes.'
Well, isn't that
nice. Come in.
Thanks.
The place
looks great.
- It hasn't changed.
- Well, there you go.
How are the girls
at the bridge club?
Old.
Well...good.
You said you were taking
a business class?
Yeah, mm-hmm, yeah.
I'm taking a business class
at the college twice a week.
I'm sure I told you.
Well, if you're sure
then you must have.
- Would you like some tea?
- I would love some coffee.
(Richard)
'Emily? I'm home.'
We're in here.
- 'Hi, Dad'
- What is it, Christmas already?
Lorelai was taking
a business class at the college
today and decided
to drop in to see us.
What business class?
Well, she told us
about it, dear, remember?
No.
(Lorelai)
'Well, actually,
I came here for a reason.'
Dad, would you mind
sitting down for a minute?
- You need money.
- 'I have a situation.'
You need money.
Dad, will you just please
let me get this out, okay?
Um, Rory has been
accepted to Chilton.
Chilton? Oh, that's
a wonderful school.
It's only five
minutes from here.
That's right, it is. She can
start as early as Monday.
The problem is that they want me
to put down an enrollment fee
plus the first semester
tuition and I have to do
that immediately
or she loses her spot.
So, you need money.
Yeah.
But it's not for me,
it's for Rory.
And I fully intend
to pay you back every cent.
I don't ask for favors,
you know that.
- Oh, yes, we know.
- I'll get the checkbook.
Thank you. You have
no idea. Thank you.
- On one condition.
- So close.
Since we are now financially
involved in your life.
I want to be actively
What does that
mean, mother?
- I want a weekly dinner.
- What?
Friday nights, you and Rory
will have dinner here.
Mom--
And you have to call us once a
week to give us an update
on her schooling and your life.
That's it. That's the condition.
If you agree, you'll come to
dinner tomorrow night and leave
here with a check. Otherwise,
I'm sorry, we can't help you.
I don't want her to know that
I borrowed money from you.
- 'Can that just be between us?'
- Seven o'clock work for you?
Perfect.
[music]
♪ That's where
the covers go blue ♪
And we get to wear uniforms.
No more having people check
you out to see what jeans
you're wearing 'cause everyone's
dressed alike in boring clothes
and just there to learn.
Okay, there's academic-minded
and then there's Amish.
- Funny.
- Thank you!
So, I told my mom
you're changing schools.
- Was she thrilled?
- The party's on Friday.
I got to go. I have to have
a pre-hayride cup of tea
with a future doctor.
How do I look? Korean?
- Spitting image.
- Good. Bye.
Bye.
God! You're like
Ruth Gordon just standing
there with a tannis root.
Make a noise.
Rosemary's Baby.
- Yeah.
- Well, that's a great movie.
You've got good taste.
Are you moving?
No, just my books are.
My family just moved
here from Chicago.
Chicago. Windy. Oprah.
Yeah. Yeah, that's
the place. I'm Dean.
Hi.
Oh, Rory. Me.
That's-that's me.
- Rory.
- Well, Lorelai technically.
- Lorelai, I like that.
- It's my mother's name, too.
She named me after herself.
She was lying in the hospital
thinking about how men
name boys after themselves.
So why couldn't women?
She says her feminism
just kind of took over.
Personally,
I think a lot of Demerol
also went into that decision.
I never talk this much.
- Well, I better go.
- Oh, sure.
- I have to go look for a job.
- Okay, good.
You should check
with Miss Patty.
- What?
- About the job.
You should check with
Miss Patty. She teaches dance.
She was actually
on Broadway once.
I-I don't really dance much.
No, no, she just kind
of knows everything
that's going on in town.
She'll know
if someone's looking.
Oh, great.
Uh, thanks.
Hey, what are you doing now?
Nothing...much.
I should throw
this away at some point.
Maybe you could show me where
this Miss Patty's place is.
Yeah, I guess so. I really don't
have anything important to..
Let's go.
So, have you lived
here all your life?
Yes. Well, pretty much.
I was actually born in Hartford.
- Well, that's not far.
- 30 minutes with no traffic.
- Really?
- I timed it.
Okay, then.
- So, do you like cake?
- What?
They make really good cakes
here. They're very...round.
- Okay, I'll remember that.
- Good, make a note.
You wouldn't want to forget
where the round cakes are.
So, how are you
liking Moby Dick?
- Oh, it's really good.
- Yeah?
- It's my first Melville.
- Cool.
I know it's kinda
cliche to pick Moby Dick
as your first
Melville but..
Hey, how did you know
I was reading Moby Dick?
- I've been watching you.
- Watching me?
I mean, not in a creepy, like,
"I'm watching you" sort of way.
- I just, I've noticed you.
- Me?
- Yeah.
- When?
Every day. After school
you come out and you sit under
that tree there and you read.
Last week it was Madame Bovary.
- This week it's Moby Dick.
- But why would you--
Because you're
nice to look at.
And because you've got
unbelievable concentration.
What?
Last Friday these two guys
were tossing around a ball
and one guy was
nailed in the face.
I mean, it was a mess, blood
everywhere, the nurse came out.
The place was in chaos, his
girlfriend was all freaking out
and you just sat there and read.
You never even looked up.
I thought, I have never seen
anyone read so intensely
before in my entire life.
I have to meet that girl.
I just didn't look up because
I'm unbelievably self-centered.
Maybe, but I doubt it.
- Did I ask if you like cake?
- Yeah, you did.
Oh, 'cause they have
really good cake back there.
(male #2)
'Goodnight, George.'
So, you were late
getting home tonight.
- Yeah, I went to the library.
- Oh.
I forgot to tell
we're having dinner
with your grandparents.
tomorrow night.
- We are?
- Mm-hmm.
- But it's September.
- So?
- What holiday's in September?
- It's not a holiday thing.
- It's just dinner, okay?
- Fine, sorry.
Red meat can
kill you. Enjoy.
So, I finished
hemming your skirt today.
A grunt of acknowledgment
might be nice.
I don't understand why we're
going to dinner tomorrow night.
What if I had plans?
You didn't even ask me.
If you had plans,
I would've known.
- How?
- You would have told me.
I don't tell you everything.
I have my own things.
- Fine, you have things.
- That's right. I have things.
Hey, I had dibs on being
the bitch tonight.
- Just tonight?
- What's wrong with you?
I'm not sure I want
to go to Chilton.
What?
- The timing is just really bad.
- The timing is bad?
Bus ride to and from Hartford,
it's like 30 minutes each way.
I can't believe
what I'm hearing.
Plus, I don't think we should be
spending that money right now.
I mean, I know Chilton's
got to be costing you a lot.
Oh, you have no idea.
Use that money towards
buying an inn with Sookie.
What about college?
What about Harvard?
We dunno that I can't get into
Harvard if I stay where I am.
Okay, enough. Enough of the
crazy talk, okay?
I appreciate your concern
but I have this covered.
- I still don't want to go.
- Why?
- Because I don't.
- I have to get out of here.
We have to pay first.
[music]
One-two-three. One-two-three.
One-two-three.
It's a waltz, ladies.
Susie, do you have to tinkle?
Then uncross
your legs, darling.
Oh, Rory, good. I think I found
a job for your male friend.
What male friend?
They need a stock boy
at the supermarket.
I already talked
to Taylor Doose about him.
You just send him
around tomorrow.
- Okay, thanks.
- What male friend?
Oh, he's very cute.
You have good taste.
Hands in the air,
not in the nose.
'One, two, three,
one, two, three''
You'll have to walk
faster than that.
You're gonna have to turn into
Flo-Jo to get away from me.
This is about a boy. Of course,
can't believe, I didn't see it.
All those talk about money
and bus rides, you got a thing
going with a guy, you don't
wanna leave school.
- I'm going to bed.
- God, I'm so dense.
That should've been
my first thought.
After all, you're me.
- I'm not you.
- Really?
Someone willing to throw
important life experiences
outta the window to be with a
guy. It sounds like me.
Whatever.
- So, who is he?
- There's no guy.
Dark hair, romantic guy,
looks a little dangerous.
- This conversation is over.
- Tattoos are good too.
I don't wanna change schools
because of the reasons
I've already told you
a thousand times.
If you don't wanna believe me,
that's fine. Goodnight.
Does he have a motorcycle?
'Cause if you're gonna throw
your life away, he better
have a motorcycle!
I think that went well,
don't you?
- Thanks for the knock.
- Can we just start all over?
Tell me about the guy, I promise
not to let my head explode, huh?
Rory, please talk to me.
Okay, I'll talk.
Don't get me wrong. Guys are
great. I am a huge fan of guys.
Don't get knocked up at sixteen
being indifferent to guys.
Babe, guys are always
going to be there.
This school isn't.
It's more important.
It has to be
more important.
I'm going to sleep.
Rory.
You've always been the sensible
one in this house, huh?
I need you to remember
that feeling now.
You will kick your own butt
later if you blow this.
- Well, it's my butt.
- Good comeback.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
- Rory, come on.
- I don't wanna talk about this.
Could you please,
please just leave me alone?
Okay, fine.
We always had a democracy
in this house.
We never did anything
unless we both agreed.
But now I guess I'm going to
have to play the mom card.
You're going to Chilton
whether you want to or not.
Monday morning, you will be
there, end of story.
- We'll see.
- Yeah, we will.
♪ Games, changes and fears ♪
["I Try" by Macy Gray]
♪ When will they go from here ♪
♪ When will they stop ♪
♪ I believe that fate.. ♪
(male #3)
'Okay. One,
two.. Oh, jeez.
I swear, I don't know,
what happened.
It's not important.
I made that dish a hundred
times. It never exploded.
Please, forget it.
Oh, God, I killed a Viking,
you should fire me
or make me pay the cost of a new
stove out of my paycheck.
- Whatever you want.
- Can't afford a new stove!
- Those things are expensive.
- Sookie, please.
I am begging you,
pull yourself together, okay?
I got no sleep last night and
I put my contacts in backwards.
Rory's still mad
at you, huh?
Hey, I'm not so crazy
about her either.
It was a fight.
Mothers and daughters fight.
No, we don't fight.
We never fight.
You told me to tell you when
your daughter arrived.
She's here and she's
sitting in my chair.
Hold on just a minute.
And you are the one
left standing.
That is a funny,
funny thing, no?
Hey, no muumuu today. You know
what's weird, I kind of miss it.
- You left a note to meet here.
- Thought you might wanna work.
- Make a little extra cash.
- Fine.
You're not giving me the "Mommy
Dearest" treatment ever, are ya?
You wanted me here, I'm here.
Should I do something or what?
Yeah, go home. Dinner's
at seven. Be ready to go.
- Fine.
Ah, my chair.
So, do we go in
or do we just stand here
reenacting 'The Little
Match Girl'?
Okay, look, I know you and me
are having a thing here
and I know you hate me but I
need you to be civil.
At least through dinner, on the
way home you can pull Menendez.
- Deal?
- Fine.
- Hi, Grandma.
- Well, you're right on time.
Yeah, yeah, no
traffic at all.
I can't tell you what a treat
it is to have you girls here.
Oh, well, we're
excited, too.
Is that a collector's cup
or can I throw it away for you?
- In the kitchen, please.
- Sorry.
So, I want to hear
all about Chilton.
Well, I haven't actually
started yet.
Richard,
look who's here.
Rory. You're tall.
- I guess.
- What's your height?
- Five-seven.
- That's tall. She's tall.
- Hi, Dad.
- Lorelai, your daughter's tall.
Oh, I know.
It's freakish.
We're thinking of having
her studied at M.I.T.
Huh?
- Champagne, anyone?
- That's fancy.
Well, it's not every day
that I have my girls
here for dinner on a day
the banks are open.
A toast.
To Rory entering Chilton
and an exciting
new phase in her life.
Here, here.
Mmm. Well, let's sit everyone.
This is just wonderful.
An education is the most
important thing, next to family.
And pie.
Joke, joke.
Ah.
- Rory, you like the lamb?
- It's good.
- Too dry?
- No, it's perfect.
Potatoes could use
a little salt, though.
Excuse me?
So, Grandpa, how's
the insurance biz?
Oh, people die, we pay.
People crash cars, we pay.
People lose
a foot, we pay.
Well, at least you have
your new slogan.
And how are things
at the motel?
The inn?
They're great.
Lorelai's the executive manager
now. Isn't that wonderful?
Speaking of which,
Christopher called yesterday.
Speaking of which? How is that
a speaking of which?
He's doing very well
in California.
His Internet start-up goes
public next month.
This could mean big things.
Very talented man, your father.
She knows.
He always was a smart one, that
boy. You must take after him.
Speaking of which, I'm gonna
get a coke. Or a knife.
Hi, how are you doing?
- I think I'm gonna go talk--
- No, I'll go.
You stay and keep your
grandfather company.
Lorelai, come back
to the table.
Is this what it's gonna be like
every Friday night?
I come over and
let you attack me?
You're being very dramatic.
Dramatic? Were you
at that table just now?
Yes, I was, and you took what
your father said the wrong way.
The wrong way? How could I've?
What was open to interpretation?
- 'Keep your voice down.'
- 'No. I can't take it anymore''
(Lorelai)
'Tonight just seems
like a nightmare.'
(Emily)
'You're dripping all
over the floor.'
Why do you pounce on every
single thing I say?
That's absurd. You barely
uttered a word all night.
- 'That's not true.'
- You said pie.
- Oh, come on.
- You did. All you said was pie.
Why would he bring him up?
Was that really necessary?
He likes Christopher.
Isn't that interesting? Because,
as I remember, when Christopher
got me pregnant,
Dad didn't like him so much.
Oh, please, you were sixteen.
What were we supposed to do?
Throw you a party?
We were disappointed.
The two of you
had such bright futures.
By not getting married we got to
keep those bright futures.
When you get pregnant,
you get married.
A child needs
a mother and a father.
Mom, do you think that
Christopher would have
his own company right now
if we'd gotten married?
Do you think
he would be anything?
Yes, I do. Your father would
have put him in the insurance
business and you'd be
living a lovely life right now.
He didn't like
the insurance business
and I am living
a lovely life right now.
- Right, far away from us.
- Oh, here we go.
You took that girl, completely
shut us out of your life.
- You wanted to control me.
- You were still a child.
I stopped being a child the
minute the strip turned pink.
I had to figure out
how to live. I found a good job.
As a maid. With all
your brains and talent.
I worked my way up.
I run the place now.
I built a life on my own
with no help from anyone.
Yes, and think where you'd be
if you'd accepted a little help.
And where Rory would have been.
But no, always too proud to
accept anything from anyone.
Well, I wasn't too proud
to come here to you two begging
for money for my kid's
school, was I?
'No, you certainly weren't.
But you're proud to tell her'
'where you got it from,
aren't you?'
Well, fine.
You have your precious pride
and I have my weekly dinners.
Isn't that nice?
We both win.
[snoring]
[sighs]
- Mom?
- I'm okay. I just..
Do I look shorter?
'Cause I feel shorter.
Hey, how about I buy
you a cup of coffee?
Aw. Yeah.
You drive, though,
okay, 'cause..
I don't think my feet
will reach the pedals.
So, nice dinner
at the grandparents' house.
Oh, yeah, her dishes
have never been cleaner.
You and Grandma seemed
to have a nice talk.
- How much did you hear?
- Not much. You know, snippets.
- Snippets?
- Little snippets.
- So basically everything?
- Basically, yes.
Well, the best laid plans.
I think it was really brave
of you to ask them for money.
Oh, I so do not want
to talk about it.
So, how many meals is it gonna
take till we're off the hook?
I think the deli spread at
my funeral will be the last one.
Hey.
Wait, does that mean..
Can't let a perfectly good
plaid skirt go to waste.
Aww, honey,
you won't be sorry.
Wow!
You-you look nice.
Really nice.
I...had a meeting
earlier at the bank.
They-they
like collars.
You look nice, too.
I had a flagellation to go to.
- So, what will you have?
- Coffee, in a vat.
I'll have coffee also.
And chili fries.
That's quite a refined
palate you got there.
Behold the healing
powers of a bath.
So, tell me
about the guy.
You know what's really special
about our relationship?
The total understanding about
the need for one's privacy.
I mean, you really
understand boundaries.
- So tell me about the guy.
- Mom!
- Is he dreamy?
- That's so 'Nick at Night'.
- I'm gonna find out anyway.
- Really? How?
Uh, I'll spy.
Coffee.
Fries.
I can't stand it.
This is so unhealthy.
'Please, put down
that cup of coffee.'
You do not wanna
grow up to be like your mom.
Sorry, too late.
So tell me
about the guy.
Check, please.
Are you embarrassed
to bring him home?
- I'm not embarrassed.
- Does he talk at all?
No, mom, he's a mime.
[Kit Pongetti singing
"My Little Corner
Of The World"]
♪ I always knew that
I'd find someone like you ♪
♪ So welcome to a little
corner of the world ♪
[music]